<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="79875" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="TripsData" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="This mod can be used to output trips data from the game into csv files" />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="This is a long description" /-->
	<LongDescription>
This mod will output Trip data by time periods to CSV files. There is currently no UI to show the data, but the csv files can be opened in Excel or other statistical softwares to create plots and graphs to better understand what is happening in your city.

The output directory of where those files will be saved is shown on the Mod's options menu. By default none of the files will be generated, they need to be selected at the menu.

There are several types of data that can be generated:

## Trip Type

Trip type is classified in four categories which are explained below. The number of trips by type is collected from the game every half hour and a file is created for the day at 11:30 pm (game time).
* **Home Based Work:** This include trips from Home to Work and from Work to Home.
* **Home Based School:** This include trips from Home to School and School to Home.
* **Home Based Other:** This consists of trips that start or end at home and go to or are from anyplace that is **not** work or school. This will include trips from home to shopping or leisure.
* **Non Home Based:** All trips that don't have home as the origin or destination. 

## Citizen Purpose

Some of the citizen purposes - as defined in the game, are collected an added to a file every half hour. Not all purposes are included, but some such as GoingToWork, GoingHome, GoingToSchool are included.

## Commute Time Frequency Distribution

Frequency distribution of commute time for all workers. The data is grouped in 15 minute bins and the file is generated around midnight every day.

## Transit

Number of passengers waiting for transit and the average passenger waiting time is saved to the csv file every 30 minutes.

## Cars

Number of parked cars at every 30 minutes is saved to the output file.

## Trucks

* Number of trucks and truck status flags (as defined in the game), for every 30 minutes.
* Number of garbage trucks for every 30 minutes.

## Smooth Speed

Smooth game speed is collected around every 20 in game minutes and saved to the day (or month) csv file.

	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/tripsdata-mod.1673785/" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="0.4" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.1.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id="" />
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>
* Added garbage truck file
* Added commute time frequency distribution
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/ruzbeh0/TripsData" />
</Publish>
